Haseeb Ullah Khan

Senior Front-end Engineer

in LinkedIn

Portfolio

I started with Web Development in 2016 and worked on small to medium applications until mid-2020. I joined Meveto as a Front-end Engineer in Sept 2020. A few months later, I was promoted to Senior Front-end Engineer. With over 3 years of experience in the industry, I have honed my skills and have a deep understanding of technologies like JavaScript, React and its ecosystem like Redux.

I am always eager to learn and grow as a developer, and I am committed to staying up-todate with the latest front-end development trends. I am confident in my ability to bring a positive impact to any project and drive results for my clients and employer.

Skills

JavaScript	Tailwind CSS	Restful APIs
React.js	React Native	AWS
Redux	Docker	Git
MUI	Postman	

Experience

Senior Front-end Engineer

Meveto Inc

July 2021 to Present

- ➤ I built a **Lead Tracking Portal** for the Meveto marketing team. The tool was used internally as a bespoke CRM.
- ▶ I built the entire **Admin Panel** for the Meveto team, both, Frontend and Backend. We initially used Electron for the desktop app but then I converted it to a web-based app using React.
- ➤ I participated in implementing a completely new design for the Meveto mobile apps. We used **React Native with TypeScript**.
- ➤ I refactored majority of the Meveto's user dashboard (Frontend). The dashboard is built with React + Redux.
- ➤ I converted 70% of the codebase to use **Redux Toolkit and RTK Query** instead of error-prone vanilla Redux implementation.
- ▶ I participated in **code reviews and training** of new colleagues.

Front-end Engineer Meveto Inc

Sep 2020 to June 2021

- ➤ I built the Meveto documentation portal. The portal documented Meveto APIs, SDKs, and WordPress plugins for developers.
- ➤ I helped transition from bootstrap to tailwind CSS at the front end.
- ➤ I took part in the majority of the **initial UI pages** that were developed at that time.

Experience

Founder Depart

Sep 2018 to Jun 2021

I built Depart for the university where I did my Bachelor's degree. It is a bespoke web and mobile app to automate most of the work related to student and faculty transport. The app can be used by travelers (students, faculty, etc.) and university administration. Travelers can use it to request transport facilities for an available route and to communicate with transport staff for any query. Admins can use it for many tasks. Several tasks worth mentioning are:

- ➤ Store and process travelers', drivers', and conductors' data.
- ➤ Manage vehicle information like scheduling routes and departure and arrival times.
- Print travel passes (cards) for travelers.
- ➤ Manage vehicle routes and meter readings to calculate average fuel consumption.
- ➤ Send real-time notifications for route changes, vehicle changes, vehicle issues, and traffic conditions.
- Trace vehicle location in an emergency.

Education

BSC (Hons) Software Engineering Sep 2017 - Jul 2021

National University of Modern Languages (NUML)

I have completed 16 years of formal education. My major was Computer Science and Software Engineering.